melbourne.vic.gov.au 2015-06-15

# Website privacy statement - City of Melbourne

This privacy statement applies to the City of Melbourne website. For information about the broader collection and use of personal information by the City of Melbourne, please refer to our Privacy Policy.

## Links

This website privacy statement does not apply to other websites we may link to. We recommend you read the privacy statement when you access another site.

## Anonymous access to our site

You can access the City of Melbourne home page and browse our web site anonymously, without disclosing your personal information.

## Social media collection statement

**Information  Regarding Your Social Networking Services (“SNS”)**

If you use your Facebook, Twitter, or other social networking sites ("SNS") account information to log in and/or authenticate with a City of Melbourne website (“CoM”), we will collect and store a unique user ID provided by your SNS. 

As a CoM website user, you can choose to log in and/or authenticate with a SNSs, such as Facebook. To do so, you must use your account credentials (typically username and password) for your SNS. Your SNS will provide CoM will a unique user ID which CoM can use to identify you on CoM websites. CoM will retain this user ID, keep it private and use it to identify you and enable your access to features on CoM websites. The City of Melbourne will not access or collect any information from your SNS profile. 

We encourage you to read the privacy policies and other statements of the SNSs you use. 

## Collection and use of personal data

The City of Melbourne website only collects or records personal information you choose to provide through our Contact Us section, subscription to various eNewsletters, initiatives or programs updates and financial transactions. As part of our commitment to customer service, we may periodically invite you to provide feedback about your experience via a survey. Any survey is voluntary and you do not have to participate.

Where possible, you have the option of not identifying yourself when entering into a transaction with the City of Melbourne. However, there may be instances where this is not feasible. For example, there is no requirement for an individual to identify themselves if they just want to report an incident (eg a toilet block maintained by City of Melbourne requires cleaning). However, if an individual contacts the City of Melbourne because they want a new rubbish bin – we are unable to provide the new bin without knowing the person’s name and address.

City of Melbourne staff use personal information collected from email and survey sources to respond to individuals and discuss their particular enquiries. Survey results may also be shared with actioning areas within the organisation to evaluate and improve the customer service experience.

Email addresses and any other contact details you provide will not be added to mailing lists without your consent.

### Disclosure of personal information

City of Melbourne will take all necessary measures to prevent unauthorised access to, or disclosure of, your personal information. 

External organisations to which personal information is disclosed include City of Melbourne’s contracted Service Providers who perform various services for and on behalf of City of Melbourne. These contractors have agreed to be bound by the provisions of the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (VIC). Information provided to these contractors is limited to contact details provided by you whilst contacting us.

We will also ensure that your personal information is not disclosed to other individuals, institutions and authorities outside Council except if required or authorised by law or explicitly permitted by you. For example, in the event of an investigation into suspected unlawful or improper activity, a law enforcement agency or government agency may exercise its legal authority to inspect the web server's records (e.g. in relation to hacking or abusive messages).

Agencies and businesses that we may need to forward your contact details to include but are not limited to:

  * Port Phillip City Council 
  * Yarra City Council 
  * City of Stonnington 
  * VicRoads 
  * Jemena 
  * CitiPower 
  * DPCD 
  * Land Titles (Vic) 
  * Federation Square 
  * Victoria Police 
  * Public Records Office. 

All above mentioned agencies and Councils are subject to privacy legislations.

## Access and correction

Requests for access to documents containing personal information and held by the City of Melbourne are handled under the Freedom of Information Act 1982 and can be addressed to the:

Manager Governance Services  
GPO Box 1603  
MELBOURNE VIC 3000

## Collection and use of site visit data

Cookies are used on our site, but they do not collect any personal information. For the most part they are sessional and just contain system-generated values to identify the user's session for statistical and system administration purposes only.

This site’s web-server automatically collects the following non-personal information (i.e. clickstream data) for statistical and system administration purposes only: 

  * your server (or IP) address 
  * the day and time you visited the site 
  * the pages you visited on our site 
  * the address of the last page you visited 
  * the operating system you are using 
  * rough geographic location (down to the city) 
  * language (eg American English) 
  * internet service provider (eg Telstra) 
  * the type of browser and version you are using. 

To the extent that this data could make you identifiable, the City of Melbourne will not attempt to identify individuals from the records the server automatically generates unless necessary to investigate a breach of law or regulation.

## Security of your personal data

This web site uses secure transmission facilities when appropriate (e.g. financial transactions). You should be aware that there are risks in transmitting information across the Internet. If you are concerned about conveying sensitive material to City of Melbourne over the Internet, you might prefer to contact us by telephone or mail.

## Contact us

Please contact us for further information.

Please contact the Council’s Privacy Officer at [privacy@melbourne.vic.gov.au](mailto:privacy@melbourne.vic.gov.au) if you have any other enquires concerning Council's privacy procedures.

You can also refer to further information at Information privacy.
